Hard Hat Days And Honky-Tonk Nights.
Urban Cowboy is a drama, romance, western film directed by James Bridges.
After moving to Pasadena, Texas, country boy Bud Davis starts hanging around a bar called
Gilley's, where he falls in love with Sissy, a cowgirl who believes the sexes are equal.
They eventually marry, but their relationship is turbulent
due to Bud's traditional view of gender roles.
Jealousy over his rival leads to their separation, but Bud attempts to win Sissy
back by triumphing at Gilley's mechanical bull-riding competition.
Bud Davis, played by John Travolta.
Sissy, played by Debra Winger.
Wes, played by Scott Glenn.
Pam, played by Madolyn Smith Osborne.
Uncle Bob, played by Barry Corbin.
Aunt Corene, played by Brooke Alderson.
Urban Cowboy is a 1980 American romantic Western film directed by James Bridges.
The plot concerns the love-hate relationship between Buford "Bud"
Davis (John Travolta) and Sissy (Debra Winger).
The film's success was credited for spurring a
mainstream revival of country music.
Much of the action revolves around activities at Gilley's Club, a
football-field-sized honky tonk in Pasadena, Texas.
The film explores themes of texas, slice of life,
blue collar, newlywed, marital problem.
The tone is emotional.